hexonet.net 2016-11-10

# Privacy Policy | Hexonet

###  I. Introduction

Data Protection is a matter of trust and importance to us. HEXONET Services Inc. and HEXONET GmbH (“Hexonet”) respects the privacy of its customers and visitors of its websites ("Users")  and is committed to protecting their personal information. Hexonet wants to ensure that the Users understand how Hexonet will and will not use the information they entrust to Hexonet. This Policy describes Hexonet's general principles for the collection and use of information of Users at Hexonet's Websites. This Privacy Policy is based on applicable privacy laws. Hexonet shall only use Users' personal data in the manner set out in this Policy. Hexonet takes reasonable precautions to avoid loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction of the data provided. 

**By visiting any of the Hexonet websites, Users hereby consent to the provisions set forth in this Privacy Policy.**

Hexonet encourages each User to read this Policy to understand their rights. Users should not hesitate to contact Hexonet for further information hereinafter at [support@hexonet.net](mailto:support@hexonet.net).  

###  II. Data collected and processed

**1.  Log files **

When  a User visits a Hexonet Website, a Hexonet Webserver collects basic User information that includes the domain of their ISP, the IP address, the browser type and version, the operating system of the computer/device, the access date/time, and the Hexonet Website URLs that the user visited. The data collected does not personally identify the User except to prevent fraud or abuse of the system. Hexonet only uses Log files for its own statistical analysis, to diagnose problems with its server and to administer its site and products. Hexonet reserves the right, to review the log files of any User suspected of using a Hexonet website illegally and/or contrary to Hexonet's Policies.  

**2\. Collected Data**

When a User signs up for Hexonet’s offered services, they provide Hexonet with their contact information. Contact information typically includes the User's name, address, telephone number and E-Mail address. Furthermore, the User agrees to Hexonet's Policies, including the Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. By submitting the data, the User constitutes consent to the use of the information for the purposes stated in this Policy. As part of the payment processes, Users also provide Hexonet with payment information that will only be used for payment and billing purposes.   

**3\. Communication**

When a User contacts with Hexonet via email or by other means of electronic communications, Hexonet may retain the content or information provided by the User in order to support and respond to inquiries and/or to improve Hexonet's services, content, products and Internet brand.   

**4.  Minors' Privacy**

Hexonet does not offer or allow use of its products or services to any individual under the age of 18 (“Minor”). Minors to be customers of Hexonet must have permission from a parent or guardian by having their parent or guardian accept the Agreements on behalf of the Minor. If a User is under 18 years of age, Hexonet strongly encourages the Minor to use Hexonet Websites only with the involvement of a parent or a guardian.  

**5\. Cookies**

Hexonet uses cookies to enable its systems to detect a User's device and to provide features to them. Users must read the Cookie Policy (Re: Cookie Policy) for more information on how cookies are used to save the preference of a User.

###  III. Use of personal information/data

HEXONET does not trade, rent or sell the personal information of any User to third parties or organisations.  

**1.  Hexonet Services**

Hexonet uses the contact information provided by a User to establish and tailor its service for that specific User. Hexonet uses payment information for payment processing purposes only. It creates and maintains other information such as customer account status, choice of services, and customer logs in the normal course of providing service.   Please note that HEXONET may use the information collected to direct notices, such as communications about purchases and changes to its terms, conditions and policies.  

**2\. Newsletter**

a. With a User's consent, Hexonet may provide them with general information that may be of interest to the User.  The general information is provided at Hexonet's sole discretion and delivered through its newsletter, which may  contain details about Hexonet's services, product offerings or other services from business affiliates, as well as, important information regarding a User's account or services. To receive the newsletter, a User needs to hold a valid and working email address.  Hexonet may request additional confirmation from a User to ensure that the User is the registered owner of the email address. To prevent misuse of User email addresses, Users may receive a confirmation mail containing a link to the final registration (double opt-in) of an email address with a User's Hexonet account.  At the User's discretion, the User can unsubscribe to the Newsletter by either emailing Hexonet or clicking the provided unsubscribe link at the end of each newsletter version.

b. Hexonet may also use User data to provide the User with system information or information about new or upgraded products through the Newsletter.    

**3\. Affiliates**

Affiliates are entities controlled by Hexonet.  Affiliates also include entities where Hexonet has controlling or common control.  In order to provide its Services, Hexonet may share a User's personal information with its affiliates as reasonably necessary. Hexonet's trusted affiliates are responsible for processing or handling some of the information Hexonet receives, such as the fulfillment of domain name registrations. Those affiliates are not authorized to use such information for purposes beyond those specified by Hexonet and are required to preserve the confidentiality with which Hexonet treats such information.  

**4\. Links**

Hexonet's Websites may provide links to third party Websites that may be maintained by companies not affiliates of Hexonet. Therefore, Hexonet is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third party Websites. Users are encouraged to understand the risks and use caution when navigating through to a third party via a link provided by Hexonet. In particular, Hexonet recommends that Users view the privacy policy posted for each website and confirm the respective website's policies. This Privacy Policy solely applies to information collected by Hexonet.

**5\. Piwik**

Website Tracking Hexonet respects the privacy of its Users. Hence, its websites use Piwik for analysing web traffic and statistical purposes. Piwik is open source software, which allows companies to review the code and functionality of the software against privacy concerns. Therefore, by using Piwik, Hexonet alone keeps control of the data of our Users. This data is stored on Hexonet's own MySQL database.  Logs and report data will never be sent to other servers by the Piwik software (see also Piwik's Privacy Policy: https://piwik.org/privacy/).  Piwik uses “cookies”( for information on Cookies see: Cookie Policy) to help the website analyze how a User uses a website. Hexonet Users will have cookies stored on the devices that they use to access a Hexonet website. The information generated by a cookie about a User's use of a website, including their IP address, is anonymized prior to its storage. Users may refuse this use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on their browser.   Hexonet will not associate the website data of a User with the personal data of a User stored for other purposes.

**6\. Whois**

Hexonet by agreement must abide by policies set forth by ICANN, which includes the collection of certain User data. This data includes the Registrants' full name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and where provided the facsimile number and in addition the creation and expiration date of the respective domain name registration and the name server information associated with a Registrant's domain name. Hexonet is obliged by ICANN to make this information available to the public via a "port 43" WHOIS and an interactive webpage. Once this information is made public, Hexonet has no influence on its use by third parties.

**7.  Disclosure**

Hexonet will only disclose personal information as stated by this policy.

a. Hexonet disclaims any intention to censor, edit, or engage in ongoing review or surveillance of communications stored on or transmitted through its facilities by Users or others. Hexonet will, however, review, delete, or block access to communications that may harm Hexonet, its Users or third parties. The grounds on which Hexonet may take such action include, but are not limited to, actual or potential violations of Hexonet's Agreements.

b. With Users' explicit consent HEXONET may share User information with selected partners/third parties to provide the Users with a better user experience, such as information about products, which might be of interest to the Users or to enable Users to take advantage of special partner programs. 

c. In order to carry out several services for the Users (e.g. in the case of a credit card payment), Hexonet may submit personal information about them to third parties, provided that it is prerequisite to obtaining the specific service.

d. Hexonet may also disclose contact information with the permission of a User when gathering and posting testimonials.

e.  Hexonet will not otherwise disclose a User's personal and account information unless it has reasons to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to identify, make contact with, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing harm or interfering with the rights or property of Hexonet, its Users, or others. Hexonet may provide information to regulatory authorities and law enforcement officials in accordance with applicable laws or where Hexonet has a good faith belief that the law requires such disclosure.

f. Hexonet will not disclose to third parties the contents of any electronic mail or other electronic communications that it stores or transmits for its Users except where:

(a) it is a matter or public safety or policy;

(b) it is in connection with the transfer of other business assets;

(c) it is required to cooperate with orders, warrants, or other legal processes that Hexonet determines in its sole discretion to be valid and enforceable; and

(d) it is necessary to provide to a law enforcement agency when the contents are inadvertently obtained by Hexonet and appear to pertain to the commission of a crime.  

###  IV. Security

**1.Transport Layer Security (TSL)**

Hexonet has security measures in place to help prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under its control. When a User places an order online, their information, including their credit card number, is protected using TSL encryption technology. This encrypts order data and is designed to aid in ensuring the accuracy and security of User information.

**2.Two-Factor-Authentication (2FA)**

2FA is a technology that improves the security of account access by employing two methods to identify a User as the legitimate account holder. The 2FA login process differs from the standard login in the Control Panel, if a User decides to enable 2FA (<https://cp.hexonet.net/cp2/downloads/2FA.pdf>).

nbsp;

###  V. After Termination

After termination of the business relationship, Hexonet will store personal information only in order to comply with its legal obligations, to resolve disputes or in cases where it needs to enforce its agreements.  

###  VI. Policy Amendments

Hexonet may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. In that case it will notify Users through its service and/or by other means, such as via E-Mail, in order to give Users the opportunity to review those changes before they continue to use Hexonet’s Services. The continued use of the website by a User following any changes to this Policy will be deemed to constitute their consent to such changes. The operative and effective version of this Policy will be the latest version available on the website.  

###  VII. Final Note

Users can access their personal information, such as the address and contact information, at any time to correct, delete or amend any of the data shared with Hexonet. Access of personal User information is available by clicking on the “Customer Login” link at the top any Hexonet Website homepage. The account information is secure and is accessible by the password defined by the User or if the User has enabled Two-Factor-Authorization, a User defined password and auto-generated code by a Two-Factor-Authorization application. If a User needs further detail of the information Hexonet holds about them or their account, as well as, needing other assistance or if a User has questions about correcting or deleting information, they can contact Hexonet via email at support@hexonet.net.
